Kolb, Frances Arick. Papers, 1955-1990 (inclusive), 1972-1990 (bulk): A Finding Aid
Papers, 1955-1990 (inclusive), 1972-1990 (bulk)
- Series IV. NATIONAL ORGANIZATION FOR WOMEN-RELATED
  - Subseries B. Eastern Region
    - NOW New Jersey [correspondence, printed material], 1974-1978; contains correspondence re: lesbian rights., 12.9.
    - Abortion [FAK notes and testimony to South Hills (N.J.) chapter of NOW], 1976, 12.10.
    - New Jersey Committee for the Observance of International Women's Year [FAK notes, printed material], 1977, 12.11.
    - [NOW New Jersey-NOW International Women's Year budget materials], 1977, 12.12.
    - NOW New Hampshire [correspondence], 1972, 12.13.
    - NOW New York [correspondence], 1973, 12.14.
    - NOW New York State chapters [correspondence], 1971-1972, 12.15.
    - NOW New York State [correspondence], 1972, 12.16.
    - NOW Albany [correspondence], 1972, 12.17.
    - NOW Buffalo [correspondence, clippings, forms], 1972-1973, 13.1.
    - NOW Ithaca [correspondence, clippings], 1972-1973, 13.2.
    - NOW Queens [correspondence, clippings, printed material], 1971-1973, 13.3.
    - [NOW] Staten Island [correspondence, clippings], 1972, 13.4.
    - NOW Pennsylvania [correspondence], 1972, 13.5.
    - NOW Pennsylvania state [FAK notes], 1972, 13.6.
    - NOW Pennsylvania [member lists, correspondence], 1973, 13.7.
    - Pennsylvania NOW [printed material], 1975, 13.8.
    - NOW Pittsburgh [correspondence], 1972, 13.9.
    - NOW Rhode Island [correspondence, clippings], 1972, 13.10.
    - NOW Vermont [correspondence], 1972, 13.11.
  - Subseries C. NOW National Board
    - Correspondence: national board, 1973-1974, 13.12.
    - National correspondence personal, 1973-1974, 13.13.
    - NOW and insurance [correspondence], 1974, 13.14.
    - NOW expenses, 1974-1976, 13.15.
    - National conference [correspondence, notes, printed], 1975, 13.16.
    - Rules Committee [correspondence, notes], 1975, 13.17.
    - Do It Now Committee correspondence, 1976, 13.18.
    - [Correspondence, notes re: November issue of Do It NOW on education], 1976, 13.19.
    - Fundraising women [correspondence, printed material re: Corporate Women Project], 1976, 14.1.
    - [Correspondence and reports re: NOW delegates at International Women's Year conference in Houston], 1977, 14.2.
    - NOW conference: Women's Economic Worth: How to Attain It [FAK speech, printed material, FAK notes, etc.], April 28, 1985, 14.3.
  - Subseries D. Equal Rights Amendment
    - ERA Freedom Train mobilization fund [checks, financial statements], 1976, 14.4.
    - ERA [correspondence, notes], 1976-1979, 14.5.
    - [ERA boycott notes, correspondence], 1977, 14.6.
    - [ERA] economic boycott notes, 1977, 14.7.
    - [ERA] economic boycott planning [notes, correspondence, etc.], 1977, 14.8.
    - [ERA] Economic Boycott Committee [correspondence, minutes, budgets, etc.], 1977-1978, 14.9.
    - Boycott contacts pending [correspondence, lists], 1977-1978, 14.10.
    - California ERA [boycott: correspondence, printed material], 1977-1978, 14.11.
    - ERA actions [correspondence, printed material], 1977, 14.12.
    - [NOW ERA boycott] publicity [clippings, press releases], 1977-1978, 14.13.
    - Boycott [supporters] lists, 1977-1978, 14.14.
    - Boycott contacts [correspondence, notes], 1977-1978 (3 folders), 14.15-15.2.
    - [ERA] data collection on organizations [notes, correspondence], 1977-1978, 15.3.
    - ERA boycott correspondence, 1977-1979, 15.4.
    - ERA boycott contacts A-L, 1977-1979, 15.5.
    - ERA boycott contacts M-Z, 1977-1979, 15.6.
    - State of Missouri v. National Organization for Women [correspondence, notes], 1978, 15.7.
  - Subseries E. Archives
    - NOW archives [correspondence, surveys, notes], 1975-1979, 15.8.
    - Archives Committee [draft agreement, correspondence], 1976-1979, 15.9.
    - NOW officer records surveys, January 1977, 15.10.
    - NOW chapter/state/task force records survey [completed surveys, correspondence], 1977, 16.1.
    - [Correspondence re: NOW's history], 1987-1990, 16.2.
  - Subseries F. Internal Politics
    - NOW schism [Majority Caucus: notes, printed material, etc.], 1975-1976, 16.3-16.5.
    - [NOW] grievances [correspondence, by-laws, copies of complaints], 1976, 16.6.
    - [Survey by FAK re: proposed NOW by-law changes; completed surveys and correspondence], 1980, 16.7-16.8.
    - The Loyal Opposition: A Feminist Commentary on NOW Politics [newsletter], 1980, 16.9.
  - Subseries G. Tully-Crenshaw Feminist Oral History Project
    - [Tully-Crenshaw Oral History Project correspondence], 1990., 16.10.
      RESTRICTED UNTIL January 1, 2040 EXCEPT TO THOSE RESEARCHERS WITH THE WRITTEN PERMISSION OF THE DIRECTOR OF THE SCHLESINGER LIBRARY.
    - The Tully-Crenshaw Feminist History Project of the Schlesinger Library Advisory Committee meeting [correspondence, notes], January 12-13, 1990., 16.11.
    - [Letter from and printed material about Alice Rossi in preparation for FAK interview], 1990, 16.12.
    - [FAK notes re: Tully-Crenshaw Oral History interview with Alice Rossi], 1990, 16.13.
    - [FAK notes re: Tully-Crenshaw Oral History interview with Wilma Scott Heide], 1990, 16.14.
- Series V. FAK WORKSHOPS ON U.S WOMEN'S HISTORY
  - [The Network: printed material], 1981, 16.15.
  - The Network correspondence, 1987, 16.16.
  - American Women's History week: documents [includes notes], 1986, 16.17.
  - Arlington workshop [correspondence, printed material], 1986, 16.18.
  - Bicentennial [printed material, notes], 1986, 17.1.
  - [U.S. Constitution materials: book II [printed material, notes], 1986, 17.2.
  - [U.S. Constitution: Units 1 and 2 [printed material, notes], 1986, 17.3.
  - [U.S.] Constitution: unit III [notes, printed material], 1986, 17.4.
  - [U.S.] Constitution proposal [notes], 1986, 17.5.
  - [U.S.] Constitution research [notes], 1986, 17.6.
  - Massachusetts: [National Bicentennial curriculum on the] Constitution consulting [correspondence, printed material, notes], 1986, 17.7.
  - Wayland workshop [notes, correspondence, printed material], 1986, 17.8.
  - Source materials: women and the Constitution [printed material, notes], 1986, 17.9.
  - Southeast Regional workshop [printed material, correspondence], 1986, 17.10.
  - Women's history workshop: Massachusetts [printed material, correspondence, notes], 1986, 17.11.
  - NEH bibliography, 1986, 17.12.
  - NEH [bibliography, notes, etc.], 1986, 1988, 17.13.
  - National Endowment for the Humanities conference: "American History: the Female Experience" [correspondence, evaluations], 1987, 17.14.
  - Women's Studies Quarterly [correspondence, paper, notes re: NEH conference], 1987, 17.15.
  - NEH [correspondence, notes, printed material, etc.], 1988, 17.16.
  - NEH lecture notes, 1988, 18.1.
  - National Women's History Week lecture materials, 1987, 18.2.
  - "The Transition From Archives to High School Classroom: the Experience of the NEH/Harvard Graduate School of Education Summer Institute on American History: the Female Experience," by FAK, 1987, 18.3.
  - Women in colonial period: documenting materials [bibliography by FK], 1987, 18.4.
  - Workshop at Coventry Junior High School in Natick, Massachusetts [correspondence, notes, printed material], February 24, 1987, 18.5.
  - Workshop [printed material, notes], 1987, 18.6.
- Series VI. OTHER WOMEN'S ORGANIZATIONS AND INTERESTS
  - [FAK professional correspondence], 1974-1976, 1980, 18.7.
  - Religion and Jewish women [notes, printed material], 1973-1976, 18.8.
  - [Printed material from conferences attended by FAK], 1976, 1978, 18.9.
  - Women's Heritage Trail of Boston [minutes], 1987, 18.10.
  - [Brochures of feminist organizations was FAK not associated with], n.d., 18.11.
- Series VII. MEMORABILIA
  - 3 feminist necklaces, 1975-1976, 19.1.
  - Abortion rights pins, 19.2.
  - Elections/political organizations/miscellaneous pins, 19.3.
  - ERA pins, 19.4.
  - Miscellaneous feminist pins, 19.5.
  - National Women's History Week pins, 19.6.
  - NOW pins, 19.7.
  - Scarves:, 19.8+.
    - ERA scarf, 1981.
    - NOW New Jersey scarf, 1978.
- Photographs removed from #1.5, 19.9.
Additional catalog entries
The following catalog entries represent persons, organizations, and topics documented in this collection. An entry for each appears in the Harvard On Line Library Information System (HOLLIS) and other automated bibliographic databases. THIS IS NOT AN INDEX.
Authors
Bendorf, Jeane; Berry, Betty Blaisdell; Boyer, Gene; Ceballos, Jacqueline Michot, 1925-; Cisler, Lucinda; Crater, Flora; DeCrow, Karen; Gardner, Jo-Ann Evans; Heide, Wilma Scott, 1921-1985; Hernandez, Aileen C.; Hull, Joan; Komisar, Lucy, 1942-; Massachusetts NOW; Myers, Mary Lynn; National Organization for Women; National Organization for Women. Eastern Region; National Organization for Women of New Jersey; National Organization for Women. New York State; Pennsylvania NOW; Pratt, Annis; Rawalt, Marguerite, 1895-; Roberts, Sylvia; Rossi, Alice S., 1922-; Seidenberg, Faith; Wood, Nan Elizabeth, 1942-
Subjects
Abortion--United States; Alexander, Dolores; Bernard, Shirley, 1928-; Bibliographies; Bonk, Kathy, 1953-; Boycotts--United States; Clarenbach, Kathryn F.; Connell, Noreen; Darcy, Lynne; Demonstrations--United States; Desaram, Carol; Divorced women--United States; Do It NOW (Chicago, Ill.); East, Catherine, 1916-1996; Eastwood, Mary O., 1930-; Equal rights amendments--United States; Faust, Jean; Feiger, Sheila; Feminism--United States; Feminists--United States; Fox, Muriel, 1928-; Friedan, Betty; Fuller, Georgia; Goldstein, Joan; Historians--United States; International Women's Year, 1977; Jewelry; Jewish women--United States; Lesbianism--United States; Lonnquist, Judith; Married women--United States; National Organization for Women--Employees; National Organization for Women--Periodicals; NOW Majority Caucus; Office politics--United States; Oral histories; Pride, Anne; Questionnaires; Reckitt, Lois; Sex discrimination against women--United States; Sex discrimination in employment--United States; Spalding, Elizabeth Coxe; Stanley, Nancy; Steinem, Gloria; Styers, Aleta; Trainor, Patricia; Transcripts; Tully-Crenshaw Feminist Oral History Project; United States. Equal Employment Opportunity Commission; United States. Federal Communications Commission; Witter, Jean; Women college teachers--United States; Women--Education--United States; Women--Legal status, laws, etc.--United States; Women--Religious aspects; Women's rights--United States; Women's studies--United States